Vikas Kalyan

vikaskalyan1811@gmail.com | +917010033792 https://www.linkedin.com/in/vikaskalyan/ vikaskalyan.com

Software Engineer with 3.5 years of work experience as SDE. Skilled in backend development, Java, Spring Boot, REST APIs, Micro services and ReactJS. Strong engineering professional with a bachelor of engineering - BE focused in Computer Science from Sri Sairam engineering college (Anna Unviversity), Chennai.

SKILLS

Java, Spring Boot, Rest APIs, C, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Junits, ReactJS, BitBucket, Postman, Jenkins, Docker, Git, UI/UX, figma.

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer II

June 2024 - Present

Comcast, Chennai, TN

- Implemented secure and scalable backend services using spring boot, ensuring seamless API integration for external systems and publishers.
- Migrated core VAST detection logic from Creative Service to Creative Detector, establishing a single source of truth and reducing cross-service dependency.
- Enhanced Creative Processor to seamlessly integrate with Creative Detector while retaining legacy service calls for controlled rollout.
- Implemented a configuration-driven fallback mechanism enabling zero-downtime rollback to Creative Service in case of detector failures, ensuring production stability
- Designed and developed OpenAPIs for the Freewheel MRM application, enabling external approval and workflows for Partner Tag Creatives using Spring Boot and MYSQL.
- Extended the functionality of the existing Programmatic Creative API to support listing, retrieving and updating Partner Tag Creatives, tailored to meet specific business requirements.

Software Development Engineer

April 2022 - June 2024

Guardian Life, Chennai, TN

- Developed API functionalities for accurate customer validation and retrieving client information.
- Enhanced compatibility by refactoring code from Dot Net to Java, ensuring efficient customer verification and data retrieval.
- Implemented API calls from client to server and then from server to backend java application to retrieve and update data based on user actions, ensuring real-time synchronization.
- Streamlined file reprocessing with Amazon s3 integration, facilitating efficient backend interaction via API calls.
- Developed the backend Java API for reprocessing the file in amazon S3 bucket based on user actions from the front end.
- Developed a robust backend system for generating ID cards, integrating seamlessly with CDX for automated mail sending..

Summer Intern Sept 2021 - Nov 2021

Ernst & Young

- Collaborated closely with backend developers to ensure the seamless integration of UI changes with existing functionality.
- Worked on managing and resolving bugs, providing timely resolutions for enhanced stability.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - Computer Science.

Apr 2018 - May 2022

Sri Sairam Engineering College, Chennai, TN, India.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Received "You Nailed it award" for Q2 overall performance.
- Received Guardian Life High Five award for demonstrable outstanding job performance.
- Came in first position with around 15000 participants all over the country in the EY scholarship program and won 1 lakh of cash prize and two months of internship in EY India in front-end development.